# 胡萝卜 青笋 白肉 猪肚 白鸡
Carrots, celtuce, white meat, pork tripe, and chicken.
# 快过年了今天给大家做一个
It’s almost Spring Festival, so we are making a traditional dish for everyone…
# 传统的老菜叫什锦砂锅
… called Assorted Soup Casserole.
# 大款的全家福
A full-sized “Happy Family Portrait”.
# 你看这里边备的料有白肉
Look at what we have prepared, white meat,
# 猪肚 熟鸡白水煮
Pork tripe, chicken, all are boiled in water
# 放点葱姜放点黄酒
Put some green onion, ginger, and some huangjiu rice wine in.
# 鸡腿煮了大约在半小时
The chicken thigh has been cooked for almost half an hour.
# 肉要煮大约三十五分钟到四十分钟
The meat should be cooked for 35 to 40 minutes.
# 这猪肚硬点 （煮）一个多小时
The pork strip is harder to cook, so it needs more than an hour.
# 这个鸡腿我们改改刀
Let’s cut the chicken thigh (to small pieces)…
# 咱们把这骨头给去掉
removing the bone.
# 好的肉要摆个面
Those quality and pretty meat should be laid out well.
# 过去讲究货卖一张皮
In the past it is said that packaging is the key to marketing.
# 这是一份
These is a portion.
# 剩这些肉怎么办呀
What about the rest of the meat?
# 这个不成材的肉垫底
Put these less good-looking pieces at the bottom.
# 这是猪的后臀尖的坐板肉
This the Zuoban meat at the tip of the pig hip.
# 这个是上片
This one is the upper part.
# 不能少于十片
Include at least 10 pieces.
# 猪肚呢一定要搁点盐
We have to add some salt to the pork tripe.
# 搁点醋 把它洗干净
Add some vinegar to clean it well.
# 丸子 肥瘦猪肉 葱花姜末
meatballs, made of fat and lean grounded pork, diced green onion and grounded ginger.
# 胡椒粉
white pepper powder.
# 盐
Salt
# 黄酒
Huangjiu rice wine.
# 淀粉
Starch
# 加点普通的水
Add some regular water
# 朝着一个方向（打）
Stir it in one direction.
# 我参加工作七一年到现在
Since I first joined work at 1971,
# 就有这道菜
… I have seen this dish.
# 应该有五六十年
It should be 50-60 years old.
# 六七十年的历史
Or actually 60-70 years’ history.
# 甚至一百多年
Or even more than 100 years old.
# 这是一个传承的老菜
This is a traditional dish and a legacy to preserve.
# 这个过去不叫全家福
This is not called “ Happy Family Portrait” in the past.
# 就叫什锦砂锅
It’s just assorted soup casserole.
# 现在为了取这好的名字 好听
We have this name now because it is a bless to hear.
# 所以改了叫全家福
So we changed the name to “Happy Family Portrait”.
# 这盘底上抹点油
Brush some oil at the bottom of the plate.
# 今天呢给大家展示一个
Today we show everyone a …
# 蒸的 叫眉毛丸子
… steamed dish called Eyebrow Meatball.
# 你看他弄完了
Look carefully on how he does this.
# 在这一刮一刀就跟眉毛一样
After he is done pulling and pressing here, the ball looks just like an eyebrow.
# 利用这虎口 推挤
Use your purlicue to push and squeeze the paste.
# 往下头抹
Downwards.
# 成为三角形
To form a triangle.
# 上锅蒸四分钟到五分钟
Steam for 4 to 5 minutes.
# 蒸上了啊
Now steaming on the stove.
# 包个虾饺
Wrap a shrimp dumpling.
# 虾馅 虾馅里边有肥膘
Shrimp paste, which includes fatty meat.
# 搁点葱
Add some green onion.
# 搁点姜
Add some ginger.
# 来点料酒 黄酒
Some Chinese rice wine and huangjiu rice wine.
# 蛋清
Egg white.
# 盐三克
3g of salt.
# 胡椒粉两克
2g of white pepper powder.
# 淀粉三克
3g of starch.
# 馅打好了啊
The paste is ready
# 蛋皮摊的要薄
The egg wrap has to be thin.
# 要想蛋皮黄多加蛋黄少加蛋清
If you want to have a yellower egg wrap, add more egg yolk and less egg white.
# 这个馅往边上来点
Fill the egg wrap towards the edge for a bit.
# 让（蛋饺）好封口
So that (the egg wrap dumpling) could be easily sealed.
# 这饺子不是挤的 是捏的
The dumpling isn’t made by squeezing, but by pinching.
# 虾饺蒸上三分钟
Steam the shrimp dumpling for 3 minutes.
# 白菜叶主要全是用白菜叶
The leaves of napa cabbage. We mostly use napa cabbage leaves,…
# 用开水给它烫稍微的过一点
… and we blanch them a little longer than usual.
# 烫完了以后拿凉水冲凉
After that, use cold water to cool them down.
# 水挤干
Squeeze dry the cabbage.
# 和粉丝倒到砂锅里头
Together with glass noodles, fill the cabbage in the clay pot.
# 把这些料放进去
Put these ingredients in.
# 海米搁的黄酒
Haimi (Dried shrimps from the ocean) which is steamed with huangjiu rice wine…
# 搁的葱姜蒸了二十分钟
…and green onion and ginger for 20 minutes.
# 这些东西都齐了
Everything is ready.
# 我们把它拿手给拌匀了
We use our hands to mix them well.
# 还有一样鸡蛋摊的蛋皮
And one more ingredient – the egg wraps made from eggs.
# 胡萝卜 青笋 冬笋
Carrots, celtuce, winter bamboo shoots.
# 切成花刀出水
Carve them skillfully and leave the water out.
# 香菇我们把它泡软
We soak the shiitake mushrooms till they become soft.
# 洗干净以后放上葱姜
After cleaning them well, we add some spring onion and ginger.
# 给它煨好了
Stew the ingredients well.
# 上锅蒸 搁点酒搁点鸡油
Steam it now with some rice wine and chicken fat.
# 现在该开始摆了
Now we start to lay out the ingredients.
# 你看这刀口都是朝上的
See, the carves are facing upwards.
# 这边摆六片
Place 6 pieces here.
# 对面再摆六片
6 more on the opposite site.
# 这样呢旋转起来就好看了
Now the dish looks beautiful when the plate spins.
# 白肉
White meat
# 猪肚
Pork tripe
# 鸡肉
Chicken meat
# 香菇
Shiitake mushroom
# 冬笋
Winter bamboo shoots
# 一定要把它处理干净
Have to clean them well.
# 丸子要码上
Don’t miss the meatballs.
# 这像不像人的那个大眉毛
Do  they look like people’s eyebrows?
# 蛋饺
Egg wrap dumpling (with shrimp paste)
# 这个全家福呢
This Happy Family Portrait…
# 装这个砂锅里装好了
… is laid out well in the clay pot.
# 胡萝卜 青笋 白肉 猪肚 白鸡
Carrots, celtuce, white meat, pork tripe, chicken
# 香菇 冬笋
Shiitake mushroom, winter bamboo shoots
# 上边是眉毛丸子
The upper part if the Eyebrow meatballs.
# 还有我们这个蛋饺
And our egg wrap dumplings.
# 一会把这（鸡）汤烧开了灌到里头
After a few moments, pour the boiled (chicken) broth into the pot.
# 这边就点火了
On this side, we ignite the stove.
# 为了防止面给破坏了
To prevent the presentation not holding its shape,…
# 我们这上面得覆盖一个盘子
… we have to cover a plate on the top.
# 把这东西给压上
Press on these ingredients…
# 别让它乱跑 让它听话
…so they won’t run away. Let them stay in place.
# 这（汤）现在可以开始调味了
Now we can season the soup.
# 先搁盐
Add salt first.
# 胡椒粉
White pepper powder.
# 就点一点糖 提鲜
Add a bit of sugar to bring up the umami/xian taste.
# 汤开的下去基本就开了
The soup is warm so it is boiled in a short time.
# 所有料都是熟的
All the ingredients are cooked.
# 等到它开锅
Wait till it reaches boiling point.
# 锅已经开了十分钟了
The soup is boiled for 10 minutes.
# 咱们掀锅了
We are removing the cover from the pot.
# 看着啊
Look.
# 大款的全家福
A full-sized Happy Family Portrait!
# 这虾真鲜
The shrimp is so umami/xian.
# 再尝尝丸子
Taste the eyebrow meatballs the next.
# 对 再尝尝丸子
Yep, try the meatballs as well.
# 所以说今天您这爱徒有福气了
Your favorite apprentice has all the happiness and luck today!
# 一个六十五岁高龄的师父
Although his master is already 65 years old…
# 还今天在灶台间满头大汗
… he is still dedicated to demonstrates his best skills, sweating a lot, in the kitchen today.
# 闻其味心旷神怡
It is such a pleasure smelling the beautiful aroma.
# 食其物美味绝伦
The food is extremely exquisite and delicious.
# 师父辛苦了
Master, thanks for your hard work today!
# 谢谢二伯
Thank you Er Bai!